[{"question":" A web application is a type of","answers":["client/server application","JSP application","database application","Java application "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" A servlet is a/an","answers":["HTML document","HTTP response","JSP","Java class "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" A servlet","answers":["runs in a JSP","runs on the client","runs on a server","runs within HTML code "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" An HTTP response","answers":["is sent from the web server to the client","is sent from the client to the web server","is sent from the servlet engine to the client","is sent from the client to the servlet engine "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To minimize the amount of Java code in a JSP, you","answers":["use HTML pages to perform the business logic","use HTML pages to act as the user interface","use servlets to handle the processing requirements","use servlets to act as the user interface "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When a JSP is requested for the first time, the JSP","answers":["calls the servlet that it is associated with","calls the built-in request object","is converted into a servlet","is converted into HTML "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" As you develop a web application, you typically use","answers":["JSPs for presentation and processing","servlets for presentation and processing","JSPs for processing and servlets for presentation","JSPs for presentation and servlets for processing "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" If you’re developing Java web applications on a Local Area Network, each developer’s computer needs these items installed on it:","answers":["Just the Java JDK","Java JDK and Java EE JAR files","Java JDK, Java EE JAR files, and web server software","Java EE JAR files and web server software "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The best way to develop Java web applications is to use an Integrated Development Environment such as:","answers":["NetBeans or Eclipse","Foxfire or Netscape","FileZilla or CuteFTP","Tomcat or Apache "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To stop Tomcat, you execute the shutdown command in Tomcat’s ?","answers":["webapps subdirectory","classes subdirectory","common/lib subdirectory","bin subdirectory "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" Which of the following URLs is valid in Tomcat?","answers":["http://localhost:8080","http://tomcat/localhost:8080","http://localhost/8080","http://tomcat/localhost/8080 "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" If you get a Page Cannot Be Displayed error in Internet Explorer,","answers":["the HTTP request can’t connect with the web server","the HTTP request can’t connect with the servlet engine","the requested resource can’t be found","the HTTP response can’t be sent "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" All but one of the following is true for a WAR (Web Archive) file. Which one is it?","answers":["A WAR file is a JAR file.","A WAR file contains all the directories and files for a web application.","When you deploy an application with a WAR file, the web server must be running.","To deploy an application with a WAR file, you copy it into its document root directory. "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The servlets for a web application are stored in this directory and its subdirectories:","answers":["WEB-INF","WEB-INF\\lib","WEB-INF\\classes","WEB-INF\\servlets "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The web.xml file can do all but one of the following. Which one is it?","answers":["Define initialization parameters for a servlet.","Define initialization parameters for the entire application.","Enable servlet mapping so a client can call a servlet using any URL pattern.","Set the web server port for the application. "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" If you have to change the port that’s used by Tomcat, you make the change in the","answers":["server.xml file","catalina.bat file","web.xml file","startup.bat file "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" You can use Tomcat’s Web Application Manager to","answers":["Start, stop, or undeploy an application.","Start, stop, or deploy an application.","Start, stop, reload, or undeploy an application.","Start, stop, reload, or deploy an application. "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" If servlet reloading is turned on when a servlet is requested, Tomcat","answers":["reloads the servlet before running it","reloads the servlet if it is a later version than the one in memory","reloads all of the servlets for the application","reloads all the servlets for all of the deployed applications "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When you use a newly installed version of NetBeans to start a new project, the project consists of","answers":["WEB-INF directory and a working web.xml file","the starting code for a JSP","the WEB-INF and META-INF directories, a working web.xml file, and starting code for a JSP","the WEB-INF and META-INF directories, a working web.xml file, and starting code for a servlet "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" If two or more NetBeans projects are open, the main project is","answers":["the one at the top of the Projects window","the one that gets executed if you execute the Run Main Project command","the one that was last opened","the one that was last executed "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When you use NetBeans to create a new servlet, NetBeans does all but one of the following. Which one is it?:","answers":["NetBeans provides starting code for the servlet.","NetBeans lets you provide URL patterns for accessing the servlet.","NetBeans lets you specify the package that you want the servlet to be in.","NetBeans lets you change the options for servlet reloading. "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When you use NetBeans to edit a web.xml file, you can either use the XML tab to edit the XML code manually or you can use","answers":["the Intellisense feature to modify the code","the Output window to set specific values","the graphical interface that’s provided by one of the six other tabs","the XML Palette window to add and modify portions of code  "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To add an existing file to a NetBeans project on a Windows system, you can use the Windows Explorer to copy the file and then paste the file into the appropriate directory in the NetBeans","answers":["Projects window","Files window","Either the Projects or the Files window","None of the options"],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To deploy a NetBeans application to a remote server, you can copy its WAR file","answers":["from the dist directory of the application to the document root directory of the server","from the WEB-INF directory of the application to the document root directory of the server","from the dist directory of the application to the webapps directory of the server","from the WEB-INF directory of the application to the webapps directory of the server "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To run an HTML page, JSP, or servlet without running the entire application, you can","answers":["right-click on the file in the Projects window and select the Run File command","select the file in the Projects window and press F6","double-click on the file in the Projects window","select the Run File command and then select the file in the Run File dialog box "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The Title tag in an HTML document specifies the title","answers":["that’s used to refer to the document","that’s used to refer to the application","that’s displayed in the title bar of the browser","that’s displayed at the start of the web page "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" Which of the following is a valid HTML comment?","answers":["// comment","\u003c%--comment --\u003e","\u003c!--comment --\u003e","\u003c/comment\u003e "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The Anchor tag that follows will go to which directory? \u003ca href\u003d\"/troubleShooting\"\u003eTrouble Shooting\u003c/a\u003e","answers":["the troubleShooting directory that’s subordinate to the current directory","the troubleShooting directory that’s in the webapps directory","the troubleShooting directory that’s one level up from the current directory","none of the other options."],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The Anchor tag that follows \u003ca href\u003d\"update.jsp\"\u003eUpdate\u003c/a\u003e","answers":["displays Update as a hyperlink","displays update.jsp as hyperlink","displays Update as plain text","displays update.jsp as plain text","displays nothing "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When you create an HTML table, one cell can","answers":["span multiple columns","span multiple rows","span just the heading columns","span multiple rows or columns "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" An HTML form can be used to pass data to","answers":["another HTML page","a servlet","aJSP","a JSP or a servlet "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" What happens when the button in the following form is clicked? \u003cform action\u003d\"grades.jsp\" method\u003d\"get\"\u003e ID: \u003cinput type\u003d\"text\" name\u003d\"studentID\"\u003e\u003cbr\u003e \u003cinput type\u003d\"submit\" value\u003d\"Get My Grades\"\u003e \u003c/form\u003e","answers":["the data in the studentID text box is passed to the get method","the user is prompted to enter a student ID","the data in the studentID text box is passed to the grades.jsp file","the grades.jsp file is requested, but no data is passed "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" How many radio buttons from the following code can be selected at any given time? \u003cinput type\u003d\"radio\" name\u003d\"address\" value\u003d\"Home\"\u003eHome Address \u003cinput type\u003d\"radio\" name\u003d\"delivery\" value\u003d\"FedEx\"\u003eFederal Express \u003cinput type\u003d\"radio\" name\u003d\"delivery\" value\u003d\"UPS\"\u003eUPS","answers":["0","2","1","3 "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The tabindex attributes of the controls on a form determine","answers":["the sequence in which they appear on the form","the index values that can be used to refer to the controls","the sequence in which they will be passed to the related JSP","the sequence in which they will receive the focus when the Tab key is pressed "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" A JSP expression can contain any Java expression that evaluates to a","answers":["String object","primitive type","Java object","primitive type or Java object "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" Which of the following JSP expressions is valid?","answers":["\u003c%\u003d request.getParameter(\"occupation\"); %\u003e","\u003c%\u003d request.getParameter(\"occupation\") %\u003e","\u003c%\u003d String occupation \u003d request.getParameter(\"occupation\"); %\u003e","\u003c%\u003d String occupation \u003d request.getParameter(\"occupation\") %\u003e","None of the above "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The following code \u003c% String[] mailTypes \u003d request.getParameterValues(\"mail\"); %\u003e","answers":["returns the name of all request parameters from the mail.jsp page","returns the first value of the mail parameter or null if none exist","returns all values of the mail parameter or null if none exist","returns the values of all request parameters from the mail.jsp page","is invalid "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" In general, you should use the Post method instead of the Get method when","answers":["the request writes data to the server","the request reads data from the server","you want users to be able to include parameters in their bookmarks","when you’re transferring 4 KB or less of data "],"rAnswer":": A","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" To use your own Java class in a JSP, you can import the class with a","answers":["JSP scriptlet ","JSP expression ","JSP directive","JSP declaration "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" Which of the following is a valid JSP comment?  ","answers":["// comment","\u003c!--comment --\u003e","\u003c%--comment --%\u003e ","\u003c/comment\u003e "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" In the code that follows, the numOfErrors variable \u003c%! int numOfErrors \u003d 1; %\u003e","answers":["is initialized each time the page is requested","is an instance variable that is not thread-safe ","is ignored by the JSP engine","is invalid JSP code "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When a JSP is requested for the first time, the JSP engine does all but one of the following. Which one is it?","answers":["generates a servlet for the JSP","generates the HTML code for the JSP","creates one instance of the servlet class","creates one thread "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When a JSP is requested for the second time, the JSP engine","answers":["creates a thread that has its own copy of the instance variables","creates a thread that has its own copy of the local variables","creates an instance of the JSP that has its own copy of the instance variables","creates an instance of the JSP that has its own copy of the local variables "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The result set retrieved by the following SELECT statement contains records that have SELECT Balance, Num FROM Accounts WHERE Balance \u003c 0","answers":["one column from the Balance table where the Num column is less than 0","two columns from the Balance table where the Num column is less than 0","all fields from the Accounts table where the Balance column is less than 0","two fields from the Accounts table where Balance column is less than 0 "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" Which of the following is not a way to insert data into a table?","answers":["an INSERT statement","a SQL script","a LOAD command","a configuration file "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" When you code an inner join in a SELECT statement you do not need to specify","answers":["the name of the first table","the name of the second table","an ORDER BY clause","a join column for the first table","a join column for the second table "],"rAnswer":": C","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" In a left outer join, the result set includes","answers":["matched rows in both tables and unmatched rows in the second table","all rows in the second table and matched rows in the first table","matched rows in both tables and unmatched rows that don’t contain nulls","all rows in the first table and matched rows in the second table "],"rAnswer":": D","type":"MCQ","category":3},{"question":" The INSERT statement that follows inserts INSERT INTO Download (UserID, DownloadDate, DownloadFilename, ProductCode) VALUES (1, NOW(), \u0027jr01_filter.mp3\u0027, \u0027jr01\u0027)","answers":["four rows and four columns into the Download table","one row and four columns into the Download table","four rows and one column into the Download table","one row and three columns into the Download table "],"rAnswer":": B","type":"MCQ","category":3}]